Edward Ortiz

Product Manager | SWE -ML | Data Scientist

1 +57-311-508-1966

✓ edwardarmandoortiz@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ortizedward/

♠ Bogota, Colombia / remote

https://github.com/edward0rtiz

Summary

Project manager with 7+ years experience and software engineer in Machine Learning focused in data science enhancing project performance by transforming data into useful analysis in financial stages and strategic operations. Programming skills in python to develop KPIs, and application of Lean Methodologies to develop features. Engage conversations with other SWE's and C-level staff to keep transparent communication, clear information of the project goals and deliverables

Experience

Machine Learning Engineer

Freelancer

2019 - Present

- Machine Learning programs: Developed ML models with convolutional neural architectures as well as implementation of regularization and optimization techniques for face recognition and object verification.
- IntelligentWarehouse: Unsupervised model that shows the optimal location to set a warehouse based on client consumption in order to reduce shipping times and gas consumption. Case of study a vegetable warehouse in Toronto, Canada. This model used scrapping from foursquare API and it is implemented in jupyter notebook.
- Commodoro: Web app that serves as professional network community for coffee farmers. (ReactJS, DjangoREST, PostgreSQL, Docker)
- Airbnb-clone: Web app implementation of Airbnb platform in Python and SqlAlchemy
- SodaSH: Custom version in C of CLI Linux systems (bash). syscalls, standard I/O, signals and interrupts.

Management PM-FI Consultant

Management Consulting

2013 - Present

Worked with clients in strategic business development, business valuation, financial evaluation for -investment and advice on effective project management some of the clients I've worked are:

- ABA Colombia: Development of strategic and design financial business plan for 2015 over a budget of 1M. For 2019 I developed the valuation plan for the acquisition of the company by FCB & FIRE
- Genval: mentorship in financial valuation for the program "Productive Migration" in cooperation with CCB (Bogota Chamber of Commerce)
- Responsify: Implementation of financial strategics, VC fundraising plan.
- National University of Colombia: Controlling and monitoring over two projects along other
 public institutions in measuring the impact of entrepreneurship by refugees in Colombia
 and quality of K12 education in Bogota public schools. Reduced the deliverable deadlines
 in 15%
- SK Othila: Accelerated the management strategy of the company by training the C-level staff as well as developed their financial budget leading an optimization of 30% in their expenses
- 1400gr Agency: Designed the financial plan of expansion business plan for LATAM.

Partner and Strategy Director

Whitecam Studio

2017 - 2019

Managed the financial and strategic activities ensuring the company core operations.
 Execution of operations, production processes in video content projects and 10 RPAS operations (commercial and industrial).

Director of Operations

Forward Fare Coffee Company LLC

2015 - 2017

Managed supply chain and operations for purchases and importation of specialty
coffee from coffee farmers in Colombia to United States. Audited over 30 coffee
farms using a model that monitored the sustainability of farms, thus creating a fair
and long term trade and relationship between the company and the farmer. Due the
logistic process implemented the company generated an additional 5% revenue
over the projected

Skills & Abilities

Data Engineering

Python, Pandas, Numpy, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Modeling

TensorFlow, Keras, Scikitlearn

Deployment

Docker, DjangoREST, Flask, Kubernetes

Business Analysis

Matplotlib, Seaborn, MS project

Others

Git, Github, Data analytics, Problem Solving, Management Consulting, Business Strategy, Strategic Planning, SCM, Business Planning, Networking, Leadership

Education

Software Engineer - ML Holberton School 2019 - 2021

Data Scientist CertificateDS4A - Correlation One
2020

Deep Learning Specialization

Deeplearning A.I

Data Science Professional Certificate

1BM 2010

Business Administration and Management

Université du Québec à Chicoutimi - EAN University 2009 - 2013

Languages

Spanish English French

Complementary Education

Technology Entrepreneurship Statement of Accomplishment

Venture Lab, Stanford University 2013

Sustainable Product Development Statement of Accomplishment

Venture Lab, Stanford University

Design Thinking Lab Statement of Accomplishment

Venture Lab, Stanford University

2013

International Business, Trade and Commerce Certification

2012

China University of Mining and Technology